Hello and welcome. My name is Peter
Borring and with me today I have Julia
Møller
and Steen Klitgård.
You've probably heard a lot about
co-pilot in the last couple of years
both across Microsoft products with
regards to new co-pilot features in the
Business Central first-party
applications as well as in the context
of the co-pilot developer toolkit that
allow you as partners to build co-pilot
features in your extensions.
In this launch session we're going to
talk about a topic that you probably
haven't heard a lot about as or done as
part of developing co-pilot features and
that is testing them in an efficient and
repeatable manner.
So
Now in general you should of course
always perform testing. I mean I hope
you do that.
And there's all the classic reasons for
doing so.
But there are some new considerations in
the world of large language models and
co-pilot features that require attention
due to the high degree of variability
involved.
So how do you for example measure
accuracy of the feature at scale across
many different user prompts?
How do you create test cases covering
real life user prompts and their intents
and ensure that you react correctly to
those or following the users intent?
How do you avoid that
iterating over your your prompts or your
system prompts and the prompt
engineering leads to unintended side
effects? Maybe you perform those
iterations because you want to improve
quality in one area but then it goes
down in a different area.
How do you ensure that user prompts even
malicious do not produce especially
malicious do not produce any harms, you
know, gets responses out of the
generative co-pilot that that contain
harms.
How do you ensure that your feature
works well across user prompts of
different languages for example maybe
you will have users who
try
or using a language
for which you did not really
initially build your co-pilot feature.
How do you assess the impact of new
model versions? So
um
LLMs even other types of models like
small language models, they are not
static, right? They evolve, there are
new versions coming out and new
capabilities, but it also means that
there could be differences in the
responses that you get back for the
exact same circumstances compared to
maybe half a year ago. So how can you
ensure that as models change they don't
impact your co-pilot features in a way
that you did not intend to.
All of this requires a lot of test cases
and test runs to cover these these
areas.
Now one of the first obvious challenges
that needs to be addressed here is then
how do you create all of your test case?
I mean that that is that is really you
know an art that you need to to learn
right but
when you want to work on
on determining the feature accuracy, you
want to collect as diverse a set of
inputs as possible. So try to to have a
you know people come up with different
user prompts
and also have because using different
people can also make sure that you
reduce the bias of certain people in the
data set itself, right? So you don't
have a dependency on that certain
biasing.
You can also take advantage of large
language models itself to enrich test
case data. So maybe you can come up and
one
one test case, one user prompt, and you
can ask the large language model to come
up with 10 variations of that, for
example.
And like conventional tests, failing
inputs are also a good case for a test
case. So, you don't just have to test
for that your co-pilot feature returns
sort of expected
results, but also test scenarios where
it's it's it's failing, right? Or should
produce failures.
Maybe maybe if it's good at creating
sales order lines, you cannot have it
generate marketing text, right? So, that
that could be
things to to have in your test.
And also, Microsoft actually has some
tooling available for helping with
generation of data sets, and also for
evaluating
the outcome of the generated content,
and we'll see that later, but that's
that's something that you can use Azure
AI Studio for, and that's especially
also nice in the context of harms, just
both getting harms test cases, and also
evaluating or scoring for for harms um
handling, basically.
Then there's Secondly, there's different
types of tests that you need to think
about, and different circumstances in
which you want to run these tests.
First, there are tests that you can
consider being sort of accuracy tests,
or think think of them as unit tests in
the in the classic context.
Um they are there to test
sort of more atomic parts of your
LLM round trips, right? So, they could
be absolute test where they assert
whether some explicit value is is um
is being returned
um or met.
You know, the outcome of this. It could
also be a grounding test where you want
to make sure that if you are asking for
you know, some bicycles for example,
that what gets returned are actually
bicycles in the inventory, right? So,
those are sort of
these accuracy test. But, you also have
quality test that you can maybe think
more of as end-to-end or integration
test that that you use more
to maybe
handle sort of user interaction
scenarios, right?
Handling these red teaming or harms
testing. So, maliciously trying to get
bad replies out of your co-pilot
feature. Or for handling bias or
toxicity, etc. And for any given
scenario, you usually have to run both
of these classes of test. So, typically
the accurate test and like unit test are
used during development and model
updates to to make sure that your
feature works. And then the quality test
are being run more for feature
validation and responsible AI, for
making sure that it behaves correctly.
Then because you need to have a lot of
test, right? To have a lot of coverage,
using data-driven tests is a way to
cover more ground. So, that's basically
a concept where you can run the same
test repeatedly, but against different
input values. So, that enables
reusability because you you don't have
to create as many test cases, but can
can inject data, so you get the
variability. And thereby, you also
increase test coverage and it also
improves maintainability because you
can decouple sort of the text execution
and the test flow from the from the
actual data.
And in the context of generative AI,
data-driven testing actually helps even
more, right? We know that large language
models are sensitive to input variations
and we want to cover how well the prompt
generalizes and adapts to various
contexts.
And we also want
coverage and variation to evaluate
various metrics of our Copilot features,
whether it's for safety or quality, or
performance, or response time, or token
consumption, etc. So, having data-driven
testing there helps a lot.
And that leads to that we really want to
give you as partners some
some tools that can help you in managing
all of these test cases and managing
using data-driven tests and and also
going down
in time managing automation, etc. of
this in an efficient way. So, in this
release, we are introducing the Copilot
Test Toolkit in preview
that allows you to test Copilot features
in an efficient way, including managing
test suites, data sets, and data-driven
testing.
It's an AL extension that can be
installed in a sandbox environment, and
you can find the source for this in our
BC apps repo on repo on aka.ms/bcapps
under the AI Test Toolkit folder.
And Julia, can you tell us more about
what partners can do with that toolkit?
Absolutely.
So, let's look the Copilot Test Toolkit
from an AL developer perspective.
So, currently, let's say I'm an AL
developer, and I have an AL Copilot
extension.
I have also coded in a way that I have
AL procedures available for testing, for
example, to access the generative
function, so I can test what Copilot
produces.
So, then inside the Copilot Test
Toolkit, I want to have a test suite
where I can gather the test cases for
multiple of my scenarios for the
feature.
And I want to enable repetitive testing
on a larger number number of cases.
So, I'll need a data set that contains
a data necessary for my test.
Then, obviously, I'll need the test
procedures, test code units that will
act on the input data for my data set.
And then inside the tool
I'll be comparing runs of the test
suite, the log entries, the results.
So, let's take a look on the interface
of the toolkit. I'll walk you through
what is part of it.
Here you can see
code and description of your test suite
as well as choices to make such as what
test runner you'll be using to run your
suite.
Then
you choose your input data set. First,
you choose the suite level data set.
But you can also choose it per test code
unit, per test line in case some of your
test code unit use different variations
of the data sets.
Here is where you choose which test code
units will be part and run
with your test suite.
You can also see and access
the data on the latest run on such line
as well as filter the log entries to
only see results from a specific test
code unit.
You can also quickly see
the latest run
and what were the results, how many
tests were executed, tests passed,
failed but also the duration and the
token consumption when generating
responses from the model.
When it comes to the actions that you
can perform on the test suite
you can run it either a single time or
run it in a batch repeated multiple
times.
You can view log entries
and viewed runs of the test suite, as
well as see the input data sets,
or export the configuration of your test
suite as an XML.
So, let's focus on the input data sets.
When you select that action,
you actually can see all of the data set
that you have imported. And to import a
data set into the tool, you upload it in
the JSON lines format,
where each line
is one input into your test.
One entry that the test procedure will
run on.
And what does that entry contain? Here
you can see an example input data set.
And each line, each input in that entry
will provide all the necessary
information for the test.
Here on the screen you can see
it has a question, a user input that we
will pass to the model.
Uh we will pass it to Copilot. Maybe
context records that you need to pass to
smoothly run your feature.
You can also have expected output there
to quickly evaluate what your what the
what Copilot returned and if your test
passed or failed.
Also,
each data set can be marked as sensitive
content. If you're, for example, testing
against harmful content generation,
uh if you mark your data set as
sensitive,
uh the inputs will not be displayed
until you click on them.
So, what happens when you're running a
test suite?
Let's imagine our data set contains four
lines, four entries.
Each test procedure will be executed as
many times as you have the entries in
the data set.
And inside your test procedure, you'll
be able to access the input from your
data set using a code unit AAT test
context.
Then, test procedures can log output
and succeed or fail as well, of course.
Each test will then produce one or
multiple log entries
that you can see in the toolkit
interface. You can see the test inputs
and the test outputs in the log entries,
as well as which test code unit and
which test procedure they belong to.
You can also download the test output to
process it further, for example, for
evaluation.
Well, now that I have walked you through
the parts of the toolkit, let's focus on
using it and creating tests. See, take
it away.
Thank you, Julian. So, let's talk about
how we use the test toolkit in practice.
Specifically, we're going to go uh how
we tested the sales line suggestion
feature, and we're going to talk about
creating data sets, writing data-driven
tests, and evaluating the results. So,
the sales line suggestion feature allows
you to input some text, and based on
that text, we'll generate some suggested
sales line to add.
And that's pretty much the feature, but
how do we actually test a feature like
this? First, let's look at how we used
to test it before we got the test tool.
So, what we used to do is we had all
these different labels. You see, this is
just a normal test code unit.
And we had all these different labels
that were defining sort of different
inputs we wanted to give uh
to the feature.
And then we had a lot of different tests
that took this input and then had some
expected data.
And you see, we had a lot of all the
these tests testing all these different
labels.
But with the test toolkit, we can do
this in just a single test.
So, I'm now here in VS Code, and as you
can see, we've extracted all these
labels out into to this JSON lines uh
file.
So, if we take a look at the file,
we'll see that we have this data file
here and in the file we have all these
different questions. These are the
labels that we saw before now extracted
out into this data file. Furthermore, we
also have the expected data. The
expected data is the is the information
we need to assert sort of that the test
went well.
And we have all these different labels
for that. So, it's important to notice
that the question and the expected data,
these are specific values supported by
the tool, but you can format this
however you want in your own
application. But if you use these, then
it'll be much easier to work with in the
tool.
So, now let's go to the test code unit
and take a look at how we use this.
So, this is our AI test and here we're
using the
just a normal test code unit and a
normal test procedure.
In this test procedure, we have this AI
test context and this is the code unit
that you use to actually get the input
that you need in your test.
So, the first thing that we do here is
that we get the question. The question
is a text. And the way we do this is
through the AI
test context and we get the question.
So, if you take a look at here, you can
see that there's a lot of different
values that we support in the AI test
context and you can take a closer look
at that and see the different values
that we support here. For example,
answer, context, ground truth, expected
data, and so on.
Now, let's go back to our test. So, the
first thing we do is get the question.
So, now we have our input. Next thing we
need to do is get the expected data. So,
similarly, we use the get expected data
to get that.
Then we look up the element expected
document number and we take the value as
a text. And we do the same for the start
date and the end date.
So, now we have our question and our
expected data, then we can call our
function.
So, we call our function here with the
question and then we get some sort of
response. So, when you're testing AI
features, you need some sort of way to
call your function and get a response
that you can then evaluate. You could
also use test test pages, for example,
where you could go through
the scenario and then sort of get the
response from that.
But but you need something that you can
evaluate and assert on.
So, what we do now
is that we use these expected values and
we compare them to the response. And
that's pretty much it for writing our
test. Now, this is all generic, so we
can run this on the data set and it will
evaluate for all of them. So, let's try
to use the Copilot test toolkit to to
test this out.
So, we're in Business Central now. So,
we'll go to the AI test suites page.
And here I've already set up a test
suite, so we'll just import that.
Now, I'll open up that suite.
And you can see here that we defined it
with an input data set that I already
imported. So, if we go to input data
sets, we see it right here. This is the
data we just saw in the JSON lines file.
So, we have the input data and we have
our code unit right here. So, the next
thing to do is just execute this.
After the test has run, you can see that
28 tests were run, 27 of them passed,
and one test failed.
Now, for this specific one, we are
mocking the response, so there's no
tokens consumed, but you would be able
to see how many tokens your feature
consumed during these calls as well if
you're running an actual Copilot
feature.
Now, to see the results of this, we
would go into the log entries. Here, we
can see all the different runs.
And we can see that one of them errored.
And if we go down
and take a look
at the end,
we'll see the error message.
And we see that it expected a different
number than it actually got. So, the
next thing to do would be to fix that
error
and then rerun the test suite.
But what if it isn't so simple? What if
we can't just evaluate it in Business
Central? What if we need some sort of
external evaluation?
Well, for some features, you might need
external evaluation because they're
difficult to evaluate in Business
Central. For example, marketing text.
When you run the marketing text feature,
it will give you a text back. How do we
evaluate that this text is correct? And
how do we evaluate that it's safe?
Well, our choice for external evaluation
is Azure AI Studio. In Azure AI Studio,
you can assess and compare AI
application performance using built-in
evaluators and create your own.
Now, this is available through a UI or
through an SDK. It's subject to separate
billing, but you can learn more about
that at aka.ms/azureaistudio.
Uh now, depending on what metric you
want to evaluate, you you would need a
specific set of input. So, for example,
if I want to evaluate groundedness, I
need the question, answer, and context.
If I want to evaluate something else, I
might need just the question and the
answer.
So, how can we use the Copilot Test
Toolkit in Business Central to get the
input that we need for Azure AI Studio?
Let's look at that.
All right. So, I'm back in VS Code, and
here I'm looking at the test set that we
used to run the marketing tests.
Uh
so, here you see it's almost sort of the
same. We have three different lines.
Here, we're using a test setup instead,
because to run the marketing text
feature, we need some sort of product
info, and that's what we have here.
You can see that we don't have some
expected data here, because we're
actually doing external evaluation. So,
here we don't expect anything, but we
just want to run the feature and get the
output.
So, if we go to our test here, we can
see it's sort of the same uh test. And
here, the first thing we do in our test
is that we get the test setup.
We then use that test setup down here to
get some facts, and that's where we
extracted from the data.
Uh furthermore, we set some other things
like format and tone, uh and that's what
we use to generate the marketing text.
But now, what's different now is that
you see this returns the text. So, how
do we evaluate this text?
Again, we're going to use external
evaluation. So, the way we do that is we
set the test output. So, to set the test
output, we need the context, question,
and answer. The answer we already have
from up here.
So, now we generate the context and the
question.
The context we can generate from the
facts, and it would be something like
this. Here are some facts about the item
and the facts.
And then the the question we would
generate like this, create marketing
text for this item with this and this.
And then we give it the format, the
tone, and the facts.
So, now that we set up this test, we set
up a similar one where it's a formal
tone. It does the same just with the
formal.
Well, now that we have that test, we can
go in and we can run it uh in in
Business Central.
So, I'm back in Business Central at the
AI test suite page, and I'm going to
import another uh suite. So, I'm going
to import the second
demo that I already set up.
And as you see, this is uh configured uh
to run with another data set, the data
set we just saw with three inputs,
and another code unit, the code unit we
just saw.
So, I'm going to execute this.
And as you see, it has run six tests.
So, the reason that it ran six tests is
because it's running both of these uh
procedures uh with the same inputs. So,
we need to run both the inspiring and
formal test with input one, and input
two, and input three.
But the more interesting thing you can
see is that now both the input and the
test output is populated. So, if we take
a closer look here, you can see that
this was our input, and here is our
output. And we can also like filter down
to for example the answer. So, this was
what was outputted by the feature, and
we now have that data.
So, what we can do now is we can
download the test output, and we can use
that in external evaluation with Azure
AI Studio.
But there's one thing that we haven't
talked about yet. What about multi-turn
testing? So far, we've always done
single-turn testing. So, we had one
input uh and one output per test case.
Now, this gives us a single
conversational turn
where the previous context doesn't
matter. What that means is for marketing
text, if we call it once and we call it
again later, then the context of what
happened before didn't matter. It's the
same sort of generation that happens. In
multi-turn, you might have multiple
inputs and outputs per test case. This
is complex conversational scenarios. You
can imagine sort of a chat scenario
where the context of the previous turn
matters.
In single-turn testing, we have one
question and one set of expected data
per test case, just as we saw.
Now, in multi-turn testing, we have we
can have multiple turns and input per
test case. So, you see the first
question and expected data and the
second question and expected data.
So, to use that in the
test tool, we also have support for
that. So, in single-turn, as we saw
before, you have a question that you can
get and then you can set an output.
Whereas in multi-turn testing, you can
do this multiple times.
So, the first turn here, we get the
question and we set the test output.
Then we call the API next turn on the AI
test context. And this is what makes it
get the next question the next time we
ask for it. So, here we can execute turn
two and now we would get a different
question and the tool would take care of
setting the test output correctly.
Let's wrap up with some best practices
when working with the toolkit and
testing your features.
First of all, write code that wraps
around your prompts and is testable, so
you can easily access your feature
through AL tests.
Ensure that your data sets have a
substantial number of entries. As
mentioned before, even slight
variability in prompts can impact how
your feature behaves.
And all entries in the same data set
should have a similar structure. After
all, the same test procedure will go
through all of them.
Test and evaluate your features often,
especially when model version changes.
Then, set your test output to match the
input needed for evaluation.
And adapt what you test
based on your feature.
It is also important to mention that
this is all part of what we call road to
automation.
For now, we have API pages in the tool,
so you don't need to access its parts
through the UI interface.
You can import and export the suite
configuration as XML files. You saw how
the imported the second test suite from
an XML file.
And we aim to improve the tool to enable
the test automation and make it even
smoother for you to test your Copilot
features with less effort.
So, Peter, what can partners do now?
Yeah. So, um there are many
circumstances that can change the
accuracy and responsibility of your
Copilot feature. So, start testing them
in a well-defined manner.
And to help you be efficient in doing
so, start using the new Copilot Test
Toolkit and data-driven testing. We're
already using these for our own Copilot
features in the Business Central
first-party application.
And as always, give us feedback and
suggestions. Thanks for joining the
session.